ALEXANDER KOPYNEC

Web Developer

alexander.kopynec@gmail.com

alexanderkopynec.com
qithub.com/kopius

Somerville, MA 🥹

413.884.5417

Summary

I have always brought a programmatic mindset to my work, but I recently discovered an underlying passion for programming itself. Writing code can be much like framing a house, cultivating bacteria in a lab, or teaching algebra to a high school student. For me, it's all about working in teams to build strong, sustainable systems.

Web Development Experience

Web Developer in Training, General Assembly Web Development Immersive (August – November 2016)

- Daily intensive workshops and practical projects
- Focused heavily on object-oriented programming
- Built such essential skills as pair programming, version control, and test-driven development

Projects (visit alexanderkopynec.com to view projects)

Bill-Splitter

Responsive web app with Ruby on Rails API that splits up a restaurant tab and records users' shares in PostgreSQL.

Sunrisr

Full-stack app with Ember client and Rails API that quizzes users on their personal affirmations. Fully componentized.

Desert Island

Photo collage site uploads files to AWS S3 via an Express API. Uses Mongoose & mLab to store metadata in MongoDB.

Other Experience

Production Carpenter, LCM Builders (2014-2016)

• Renovated homes; trained & mentored junior carpenters

Co-Founder, Fresh Dragon Games (2013-2014)

• Designed, prototyped, and marketed debut product

Special Projects Manager, uAspire (2011-2012)

• Developed new systems to drive organizational growth

Skills

Languages & Core Web Technologies

- HTML5
- CSS3 | Sass
- JavaScript ES6
- jQuery | AJAX
- Ruby
- Node.js

Frameworks

- Ember.js
- Rails | Express.js

Database Technologies

PostgreSQL | MongoDB

Other Technologies

- Handlebars | Bootstrap
- Mongoose | Heroku
- Amazon Web Services

Education

Intensive Introduction to Computer Science in Java Harvard Summer School, 2016

BA in Biology

Williams College, 2009 (Summa cum laude / GPA: 3.8)